Guide to the Harry Weinberger Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Original accession, 1915-1943
  - Provincetown Players
    - Correspondence
      - Geddes, Virgil (2), 1929 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Glasspell, Susan (3), 1924 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Grossman, Moses H. (1), 1920 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Hopkins, Arthur (12), 1922-1933 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Kenton, Edna (4), 1923 (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - Macgowan, Kenneth (28), 1924-1925 (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - New York City Magistrates' Court (3), 1922 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - New York State (13), 1922, 1924 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - O'Neill, Eugene (9), 1921, 1923, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - The Provincetown Players (65), 1920-1926, 1928-1931 (Box 41, Folder 9-10)
      - Shubert Enterprises (7), 1929 (Box 41, Folder 11)
      - Tax dispute (re: claim for abatement of Federal War Tax) (34), 1921-1923 (Box 41, Folder 12)
      - Throckmorten, Cleon (3), 1923 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Legal papers
      Weinberger, whose interest in the theatre extended beyond mere legal questions, was intimately involved with the Provincetown Players and their work. He was close to founder George Cram Cook and his wife Susan Glasspell, and also to Eugene O'Neill. Weinberger was legal advisor and one of the directors of the Experimental Theatre, an organization growing out of the Provincetown Players. Papers concerning this group as well as the Provincetown Players are filed in this section.
      As attorney for the Provincetown Players, Weinberger was involved in two disputes of interest. One involved the payment of the Federal War Tax on tickets. Weinberger claimed that the tax was inapplicable because the Provincetown Players was a club and not a theatre.
      Weinberger successfully used the same defense when the Provincetown Players were twice charged with violating the "Sabbath law" by presenting plays on Sunday.
      - 1916, 1920-1924 (Box 41, Folder 14)
      - Tax dispute, 1919, 1921-1923 (Box 41, Folder 15)
      - Tax dispute: miscellaneous, Undated (Box 41, Folder 16)
      - New York vs. Provincetown Players, 1920 (Box 41, Folder 17)
      - Provincetown Players vs. D. Bierne, 1920-1921 (Box 41, Folder 18)
      - New York vs. Fitzgerald/Turkel, 1922-1923 (Box 41, Folder 19)
      - Experimental Theatre, 1924-1930 (Box 41, Folder 20-23)
      - Experimental Theatre: miscellaneous, Undated (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1922-1923, 1929, 1945 (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - Promotional materials (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - Purdy, Elias
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, and miscellaneous papers concerning New York vs. Elias Purdy. Purdy was charged with allowing his·daughter to engage in immoral practices. He retained Weinberger as his attorney.
    - Correspondence
      - Berliner, Max (1), 1917 (Box 41, Folder 27)
      - New York City Magistrates' Court (2), 1917 (Box 41, Folder 27)
      - New York State, Richmond County District Attorney (9), 1917 (Box 41, Folder 27)
      - Purdy, Elias W. (17), 1917-1918 (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - Legal papers, 1917 (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - Rangel, Jesus M.
    The papers consist of letters, notes, clippings, and miscellaneous papers.
    In 1913 Jesus Maria Rangel, Charles Cline, Abraham Cisneros, Pedro Perales, Jesus Gonzales, and Leonardo Vasquez attempted to enter Mexico from Texas to take part in the revolution against Diaz. The six men were captured in a fight with Texas authorities in which a deputy sheriff was killed. They were convicted of conspiracy to murder and sentenced to the Texas State Penitentiary.
    After these men had served their minimum sentences, Weinberger began to work for their release. He waged a vigorous letter-writing campaign to create a demand for their pardon. He gained support from prominent individuals and labor organizations in both the United States and Mexico. To support the request for pardons for Rangel and the others, Weinberger pointed out that they had been model prisoners and had served their minimum terms. He also claimed that there was a lack of evidence that the men had actually committed murder and that their convictions were due to anti-Mexican prejudice. In 1926, Texas Governor Miriam A. Ferguson granted full pardons to the six men.
    Due to the efforts of Weinberger and others, interest in this case was widespread. Among those concerned with the release of Rangel and the others were William A. Black, Alice Stone Blackwell, Roberto Haberman, Mercer C. Johnston, Daniel Kiefer, and Alvaro Obregon.
    - Correspondence
      - A-P, R-U, W, Z (114), 1919-1926 (Box 42, Folder 1-6)
      - Abbott, Leonard D. (4), 1921, 1926 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - American Civil Liberties Union (29), 1921-1926 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - American Federation of Labor (20), 1922-1926 (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - American Fund for Public Service (20), 1924-1926 (Box 42, Folder 9)
      - Baldwin, Roger
        See: American Civil Liberites Union, box 42, folder 7
      - Bernstein, Rose (18), 1921-1926 (Box 42, Folder 10)
      - Black, William A. (146), 1920-1926 (Box 42, Folder 11-15)
      - Blackwell, Alice Stone (28), 1922-1926 (Box 42, Folder 16)
      - Brannin, Carl (2), 1923 (Box 42, Folder 17)
      - Calles, P. Elias (3), 1922, 1924-1925 (Box 42, Folder 17)
      - Carrillo, A. P. (4), 1925 (Box 42, Folder 17)
      - Capers, William T. (1), 1924 (Box 42, Folder 18)
      - Chisolm, B. Ogden (2), 1925 (Box 42, Folder 18)
      - Cisneros, Abraham (31), 1921-1926 (Box 42, Folder 19)
      - Cline, Charles (58), 1919-1926 (Box 42, Folder 20-22)
      - Colquitt, O. B. (3), 1925 (Box 42, Folder 23)
      - Culberson, Charles A. (2), 1922 (Box 42, Folder 23)
      - Danziger, Samuel (4), 1921 (Box 42, Folder 24)
      - Davidson, T. W. (3), 1924 (Box 42, Folder 24)
      - Debs, Eugene V. and Theodore (5), 1925 (Box 42, Folder 24)
      - DeSilver, Albert (1), 1919 (Box 42, Folder 25)
      - Ferguson, Miriam A. (22), 1924-1926 (Box 42, Folder 25)
      - Flynn, Elizabeth G.
        See: Americans' Fund for Public Service, box 42, folder 9
      - Garner, John (1), 1922 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - General Defense Committee (7), 1920-1921 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Gompers, Samuel, 1920-1921
        See: American Federation of Labor, box 42, folder 8
      - Gonzales, Jesus (6), 1922, 1924-1926 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Grosser, Philip B. (15), 1922-1924 (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Haberman, Roberto (65), 1921-1926 (Box 43, Folder 3-4)
      - Hall, Covington (16), 1919, 1922, 1925 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Hall, W. C. (2), 1921 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Haltom and Haltom (3), 1919-1920 (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - Hobby, W. P. (3), 1919 (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - Huntington, Henry S. (1), 1924 (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - Idar, C. N. (1), 1926 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - International Ladies Garment Workers' Union (4), 1925 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - Johnston, Mercer G. (13), 1924-1925 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - Kiefer, Daniel (9), 1919, 1921 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      - Kovner, Hilda (10), 1919, 1922, 1925 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      - LaGuardia, Fiorella H. (3), 1924 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      - Lane, Hunter P. (3), 1922 (Box 43, Folder 11)
      - League for Mutual Aid (3), 1925 (Box 43, Folder 11)
      - Lowe, Caroline (9), 1925-1926 (Box 43, Folder 11)
      - Martin, W. P. (2), 1921 (Box 43, Folder 12)
      - Morones, Luis N. (8), 1921-1922 (Box 43, Folder 12)
      - Nealon, Joseph M. (1), 1924 (Box 43, Folder 12)
      - Neff, Pat M. (43), 1921-1924 (Box 43, Folder 13)
      - Oberchain, Lida C. (3), 1925 (Box 43, Folder 14)
      - Obregon, Alvaro (12), 1921-1923 (Box 43, Folder 14)
      - Perales, Pedro (21), 1921-1925 (Box 43, Folder 15)
      - Pan-American Federation of Labor (12), 1922, 1924 (Box 43, Folder 16)
      - Pinochot, Amos (12), 1923-1924 (Box 43, Folder 17)
      - Pinochot, Gifford (5), 1923 (Box 43, Folder 17)
      - Rangel, Jesus M. (80), 1919-1926 (Box 43, Folder 18-20)
      - Rubio, G. (5), 1925 (Box 43, Folder 21)
      - Sheppard, Morris (10), 1921-1922 (Box 43, Folder 21)
      - Soto y Gama, A. Diaz (3), 1922 (Box 43, Folder 22)
      - Steffens, Lincoln (11), 1921 (Box 43, Folder 22)
      - Teagle, C. A. (22), 1920-1925 (Box 43, Folder 23)
      - Tellez, Manuel C. (18), 1921-1925 (Box 43, Folder 24)
      - Texas, State of (28), 1919, 1921, 1923, 1925-1926 (Box 43, Folder 25)
      - Vasconcelos, Jose (4), 1922 (Box 43, Folder 26)
      - Vasquez, Leonardo L. (6), 1922-1925 (Box 43, Folder 26)
      - Watson, Thomas E. (2), 1921 (Box 43, Folder 26)
    - Statements regarding J. M. Rangel et al., Undated (Box 43, Folder 27)
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings, 1921, 1923-1926, undated (Box 43, Folder 28)
    - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 43, Folder 29)
  - Rasmussen, Rasmus
    The papers consist of letters. Rasmussen, whose real name was C. E. Augustson, was denied entrance to the United States and held for deportation as an enemy alien and an anarchist. After a long detention, Weinberger secured his release on bond and later arranged for his deportation to Rotterdam.
    - Correspondence
      - Andreyeff, Wasily (2), 1918-1919 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - Cohn, Michael A. (1), 1919 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor (1), 1919 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - France, Ambassador of (5), 1919 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - National Surety Co. (6), 1919 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - Pearson's Magazine (3), 1919 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - Rasmussen, Rasmus (26), 1919, 1922 (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - Switzerland, Legation of (2), 1919 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - U.S. Department of Justice (2), 1919 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (27), 1919 (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - U.S. Department of State (3), 1919 (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - Unidentified (4), 1919 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Reitman, Ben L.
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, and miscellaneous papers New York vs. Ben L. Reitman, 1916-1917. Reitman was charged with intent to sell a book on birth control called Limitation of Offspring. Weinberger succeeded in obtaining an acquital.
    - Correspondence
      - B, E, O, W (4), 1917 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - Reitman, Ben L. (3) (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Legal papers, 1916 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Rey, Manuel
    See: St. John, Vincent, box 45, folder 20
    See: St. John, Vincent, box 46, folder 2
  - Rivera, Librado
    The papers consist of letters, clippings, and miscellaneous papers concerning United States vs. Librado Rivera, 1920-1923. Rivera, along with Ricardo and Enrique Flores Magon, was convicted under the war-time Espionage Law for printing articles advocating revolution in the periodical Regeneracion. Weinberger sought to obtain his release and was successful in 1923.
    - Correspondence
      - F, H, M, N, R, T, U (19), 1920-1923 (Box 44, Folder 8)
      - American Federation of Labor (2), 1923 (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - Bernstein, Rose (2), 1923 (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - Blackwell, Alice Stone (2), 1923 (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - Daughetry, Harry M.
        See: U.S. Department of Justice, box 44, folder 14
      - Haberman, Roberto (8), 1923 (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - Harding, Warren G. (4), 1922-1923 (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - Kovner, Hilda (2), 1920 (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - Munguia, Refugia R. (2), 1922 (Box 44, Folder 11)
      - Obregon, Alvaro (3), 1923 (Box 44, Folder 11)
      - Pepper, James W. (5), 1923 (Box 44, Folder 11)
      - Rivera, Antonio (3), 1922 (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - Rivera, Librado (25), 1920-1924 (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - Tellez, Manuel C. (17), 1922-1923 (Box 44, Folder 13)
      - U.S. Department of Justice (12), 1920-1923 (Box 44, Folder 14)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (8), 1922-1923 (Box 44, Folder 15)
      - U.S. Department of State (5), 1923 (Box 44, Folder 15)
      - U.S. Penitentiary, Leavenworth, Kansas (4), 1922-1923 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, newspaper clippings (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Rosansky, Hyman
    See: Abrams, Jacob box 2, folder 8
  - Ross, Edwin J.
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, and miscellaneous papers concerning New York vs. Edwin J. Ross, 1917. Ross, a physical fitness expert and author of Continence in Marriage and What Every Boy Should Know, was charged with publishing obscene literature. Weinberger prepared a brief for Ross' defense.
    - Correspondence
      - New York City, Court of Special Sessions (3), 1917 (Box 44, Folder 17)
      - Ross, Edwin J. (2), 1917 (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - Legal papers, 1917 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Rotman, Sarah
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, and miscellaneous papers. Rotman was held as an alien likely to become a public charge. Weinberger secured her release.
    - Correspondence
      - Phillips, Gussie (2), 1921 (Box 44, Folder 20)
      - Rotman, Louis (3), 1921 (Box 44, Folder 20)
      - Schwartzberg, Mrs. (3), 1921 (Box 44, Folder 20)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (4), 1921 (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - Legal papers, 1921 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Sadokierski, Joseph (3), 1917 (Box 44, Folder 22)
    The papers consist of letters concerning New York vs. Joseph Sadokierski, 1917. Weinberger acted as attorney for Sadokierski, charged with casting contempt on the flag of the United States.
  - St. John, Vincent
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, clippings, and miscellaneous papers.
    Vincent St. John, Charles Ashleigh, Giovanni Baldazzi, Jack Law, and Manuel Rey were members of the International Workers of the World (I. W. W.). They were charged, along with a hundred other members of the International Workers of the World (I. W. W.) with conspiracy to obstruct or violate the Selective Service and Espionage Acts. Clarence Darrow was attorney for the defendants. They were convicted in the United States Court in Chicago. Weinberger was retained to represent Baldazzi by the General Italian Committee of Defense and the Union of Italian Workers. He was retained by the Workers' Defense Union to represent Ashleigh, Law, and St. John. He was retained by the Political Prisoners Defense and Relief Committee to represent Manuel Rey.
    In January 1922, Weinberger and the Italian Royal Embassy obtained executive clemency for Baldazzi and he was deported to Italy in February. Ashleigh was deported to England in February 1922. Rey was deported to Spain in 1923. Law had been granted executive clemency in December 1921. Weinberger worked to obtain pardon for St. John until April 1922, when he was asked to withdraw from the case.
    - Correspondence
      - A-D, F-I, L-N, P, R-W (68), 1921-1923 (Box 45, Folder 1-4)
      - Abbott, Leonard D. (3), 1921 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - American Civil Liberties Union (13), 1921-1923 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - Ashleigh, Charles (14), 1921-1922 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - Baldazzi, Giovanni (40), 1921-1922, 1924, undated (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Baldwin, Roger N.
        See: American Civil Liberties Union, box 45, folder 5
      - Blossom, Frederick A.
        See: Workers' Prison Relief Committee, box 45, folder 31
      - British Embassy, Washington, D.C. (5) (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - Christensen, Otto (24), 1921-1922, 1924 (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - Cook, C. V. (3), 1921 (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - Darrow, Clarence (9), 1921-1922 (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - Daugherty, Harry M.
        See: U.S. Department of Justice, box 45, folder 24
      - DeSilver, Albert
      - Flynn, Elizabeth G.
        See: Workers' Defense Union, box 45, folders 29-30
      - General Defense Committee (25), 1921-1922, 1924 (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - Hapgood, Norman (3), 1921 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - Harding, Warren G. (16), 1921-1922 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - Harlan, Esther (1), 1921 (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - Holmes, John Haynes (1), 1921 (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - Inglis, Agnes (2), Undated (Box 45, Folder 13)
      - Italian Defense Committee (63), 1921-1922, 1924 (Box 45, Folder 14)
      - Italian Embassy, Washington, DC (6), 1921-1922 (Box 45, Folder 15)
      - Johnson, Albert (1), 1921 (Box 45, Folder 15)
      - Johnson, Hiram W. (1), 1922 (Box 45, Folder 15)
      - Kelly, M. Clyde (1), 1921 (Box 45, Folder 16)
      - Kiefer, Daniel (2), 1921 (Box 45, Folder 16)
      - Law, Jack (11), 1921-1922 (Box 45, Folder 17)
      - Law, Madeleine (18), 1921-1922 (Box 45, Folder 17)
      - London, Meyer (5), 1922 (Box 45, Folder 18)
      - Nebeker, Frank K. (7), 1921 (Box 45, Folder 18)
      - Pearson's Magazine (3), 1921 (Box 45, Folder 19)
      - Pennsylvania Committee for Political Prisoners (6), 1922 (Box 45, Folder 19)
      - Rey, Manuel (28), 1921-1923 (Box 45, Folder 20)
      - St. John, Vincent (38), 1921-1922 (Box 45, Folder 21)
      - Sarnoff, Lillie (9), 1922 (Box 45, Folder 22)
      - Sheridan, Clare (4), 1921 (Box 45, Folder 22)
      - Spanish Embassy, Washington, D.C. (16), 1922 (Box 45, Folder 23)
      - U.S. Department of Justice (13), 1921-1922 (Box 45, Folder 24)
      - U.S. Department of Justice, Attorney General (29), 1921-1922 (Box 45, Folder 25)
      - U.S. Department of Justice, Pardon Attorney (47), 1921-1922 (Box 45, Folder 26-27)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (33), 1921-1923 (Box 45, Folder 28)
      - Workers' Defense Union (41), 1921-1922, 1924 (Box 45, Folder 29-30)
      - Workers' Prison Relief Committee (5), 1922 (Box 45, Folder 31)
    - Legal papers, 1920-1922 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Pardon applications by Ashleigh, Baldazzi, Law, Rey, and St. John, 1920 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings, 1919, 1921-1922 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Notes (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Sanchez, Ramon
  - Santamaria, Placido
  - Schlesinger, Edward
    The papers consist of letters. Weinberger obtained a discharge from the New York State Guard for Schlesinger on the grounds that he was underage when he enlisted.
    - Boudin and Liebman (1), 1917 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - New York State Guards (3), 1917 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Schlesinger, Frank (2), 1917 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Schlesinger, John B. (2), 1917 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Schneiderman, Morris
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, and notes concerning United States vs. Morris Schneiderman, 1920. Schneiderman was charged with being an anarchist and communist. Weinberger secured his release because of a lack of evidence.
    - Correspondence
      - Schneiderman, Morris (6), 1920 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (1), 1920 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Legal papers, 1920 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Schwartz, Jacob
  - Selwyn and Co.
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, and miscellaneous papers concerning Selwyn and Company and American Play Company vs. Hollywood Plays, 1938-1941. Weinberger represented Selwyn and Company and the American Play Company in a dispute with Hollywood Plays over the sale of the motion picture rights to Avery Hopwood's play Fair and Warmer. Weinberger obtained a judgment in favor of his clients in 1941.
    - Correspondence
      - American Play Co. (13), 1940-1941 (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - Brennan and Deak (18), 1939-1941 (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - Century Play Co., Inc. (27), 1938-1941 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - Gaige, Crosby (5), 1940-1941 (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - Metro Goldwyn Mayer Pictures, Legal Department (3), 1940-1941 (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - New York State Supreme Court (2), 1941 (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - Schwebel, Max (44), 1939-1941 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Legal papers, 1939-1941 (Box 46, Folder 14-20)
    - Notes (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Sergi, Salvatore
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, and notes. Sergi was held for deportation to Italy because of his anarchistic beliefs. Weinberger aided Sergi in obtaining bail and a hearing, but he was dismissed before the proceedings were completed.
    - Correspondence
      - Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor
        See: League for the Amnesty of Political Prisoners, box 47, folder 1
      - Groot, V. L. (12), 1918-1919 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Guerriosio, John (1), 1918 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - League for the Amnesty of Political Prisoners (1), 1918 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Marinelli, Luigi (1), 1918 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Sergi, Salvatore (8), 1918-1919 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (11), 1918-1919 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Legal papers, 1918 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Sernaker, Bernard
    The papers consist of letters. Sernaker was being held for deportation to Russia. Weinberger succeeded in having him released on bail and eventually arranged for him to go to Germany at his own expense.
    - Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor
      See: League for the Amnesty of Political Prisoners, box 47, folder 4
    - Gershkowitz, Sarah (8), 1920-1921 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - League for the Amnesty of Political Prisoners (3), 1920 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Lewis, William H. (2), 1920 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Sernaker, Bernard (11), 1920 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (27), 1920 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Shimuni, Petrus
    The papers consist of letters. Shimuni was held for deportation as an alien likely to become a public charge. He declared that he had been defrauded of $1600 by S. N. Hanna. Weinberger could not bring suit against Hanna because the action would have to take place in New Jersey.
    - American Civil Liberties Union (1), 1920 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Hanna, S. N. (1), 1919 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Shimuni, Petrus (8), 1919-1920 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (7), 1919-1920 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Simpson, Samuel W.
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, and miscellaneous papers. Simpson, a member of the Society to Lower Rents and Reduce Taxes on Homes, was fined for distributing handbills on a public street. Weinberger obtained a reversal of the decision by arguing that the ordinance under which Simpson was fined concerned distribution of advertising material, while Simpson was distributing petitions.
    - Correspondence
      - Manhattan Single Tax Club (3), 1914-1915 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - New York City Board of Aldermen (3), 1914 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - New York Law Journal (1), 1914 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Pendry, William H. (1), 1914 (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - The Public (1), 1914 (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Rosalsky, Otto (1), 1914 (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Simpson, Samuel W. (8), 1914-1915 (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Society to Lower Rents (3), 1913-1915 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Legal papers, 1914-1915 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Slivinski, Victor
    The papers consist of letters. Weinberger was retained by the League for the Amnesty of Political Prisoners to try to obtain admission to the United States for Slivinski. He was refused admission on the grounds that he was a stowaway without a passport, suffering from a dangerous disease, a convicted criminal, and likely to become a public charge.
    - Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor
      See: League for the Amnesty of Political Prisoners, box 47, folder 10
    - League for the Amnesty of Political Prisoners (1), 1920 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (2), 1920 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Soelter, Herman R.
    The papers consist of letters. Weinberger was consulted concerning Soelter's arrest for draft delinquency.
    - Soelter, Herman R. (5), 1919 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - U.S. Department of Justice (1), 1919 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Stange, Hugh